Guide to the Andover Theological Seminary Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
Andover Theological Seminary Records
1780-2003
1807-1965
RG 275
Yale University Divinity School Library
100
(181 boxes)
These are the official archives of Andover Theological Seminary, a seminary with Congregational roots that affiliated with the Newton Theological Institution in 1965 to become Andover Newton Theological School.
Andover Theological Seminary
Biographical / Historical
Andover Theological Seminary was founded in 1807. The origin of the school can be traced to Phillips Academy, which was established in 1778 at Andover, Massachusetts. Specific instruction in divinity was provided in 1794 when a legacy was received for the support of a professor of divinity. In 1807, additional funds made possible the founding of a separate department of divinity. The following year, the theological institution known as Andover Theological Seminary was opened for instruction. In 1907 the Seminary transferred to Harvard University. In 1931 the Seminary transferred to Newton Centre, and became affiliated with Newton Theological Institution to form Andover Newton Theological School. In 1965 the two schools formally merged.
1778 Phillips Academy founded in Andover, Massachusetts
1807 Department of Divinity established at Phillips Academy (founding of Andover Theological Seminary)
1825 Newton Theological Institution founded in Newton Centre, Massachusetts
1907 Andover Theological Seminary relocates to Cambridge, Massachusetts and establishes ties with Harvard University
1931 Andover Theological Seminary relocates to Newton Center, Massachusetts at invitation of Newton Theological Institution
1965 Andover Theological Seminary and Newton Theological Institution formally merge to form the Andover Newton Theological School
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from Andover Newton Theological School, 2017
Scope and Contents
These are the official archives of Andover Theological Seminary, a seminary with Congregational roots that affiliated with the Newton Theological Institution in 1965 to become Andover Newton Theological School. The archives of the Andover Theological Seminary are organized according to its governance and structure. The records have been maintained in the order in which they were received from Andover Newton Theological School.
Arrangement
Organized into eleven series: I. Boards of Trustees and Visitors, II. Faculty, III. Students, IV. Alumni, V. Financial, VI. Legal, VII. Library, VIII. History, IX. Images, X. Publications, XI. Related Organizations.
- Boards of Trustees and Visitors, Series I
  - Minutes
    - Phillips Academy re: theological school (volumes 1-3), 1807–1940 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
    - Phillips Academy re: theological school (volumes 1-3), 1808–1836 (Box 21)
    - Phillips Academy re: theological school (volumes 1-3), 1808–1827 (Box 22)
    - Phillips Academy re: theological school (volumes 1-3), 1826–1842 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Phillips Academy re: theological school (volumes 1-3), 1841–1907 (Box 47–48)
    - Andover Theological Seminary, 1907–1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Andover Theological Seminary: [items removed from #2.1], 1907–1940 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Andover Theological Seminary, 1941–1950 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Andover Theological Seminary, 1941–1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Andover Theological Seminary, 1953–1965 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
    - re: joint meeting with Newton Theological Institute, 1953–1965 (Box 4, Folder 5-7)
    - Directors of Andover Newton Funds, 1936–1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Committees
    - Committee on Appropriation of Charity to Indigent Students, 1845 (Box 144, Folder 12)
    - Committee on Deeds of Gift and Donations, 1855–1856 (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
    - Committee on Deeds of Gift and Donations, 1856 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Committee on Deeds of Gift and Donations, 1856, 1862 (Box 7)
    - Committee on Deeds of Gift and Donations, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Committee on Deeds of Gift and Donations, 1885 (Box 7)
    - Committee on the State of the Theological Seminary, 1845–1846 (Box 144, Folder 13)
    - Endowment Committee, ca.1913-1921 (Box 144, Folder 18)
  - Faculty reports
    - ARNOLD, William R., 1921–1940 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - CADBURY, Henry J., 1921 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - CHURCHILL, John W., 1869-1899, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 3-6)
    - DAY, Charles O., 1902–1908 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - EMERSON, Ralph, 1830–1853 (Box 8, Folder 8-9)
    - EVANS, Daniel, 1912–1921 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - FITCH, Albert Parker, 1912–1916 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - GATES, Owen H., 1912–1913 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - HICKS, Edward Y., 1884–1917 (Box 8, Folder 13-15)
    - MOORE, George F., 1884-1900, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 16-17)
    - MURDOCK, James, 1822–1827 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - PHELPS, Austin, 1849–1886 (Box 8, Folder 19-20)
    - PLANTIER, John W., 1902-1920, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - PORTER, Ebenezer, 1812-1833, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 22-23)
    - ROBINSON, Edward, 1821-1835, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - RYDER, William H., 1889–1917 (Box 8, Folder 25-26)
    - SKINNER, Thomas H., 1832–1835 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - SMYTH, Egbert C., 1864-1903, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 28-30)
    - SPERRY, Willard L., 1921 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - STOW, Calvin, 1853 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - STUART, Moses, 1810–1846 (Box 8, Folder 33-37)
    - TUCKER, William J., 1881–1893 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - WOODS, Leonard, 1811-1847, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 39-46)
  - Other records
    - Other papers: general, n.d. (Box 143)
    - Supporting documents: Board of Trustees, 1780–1813 (Box 8, Folder 47-50)
    - Supporting documents: Board of Trustees, 1814–1908 (Box 9–14)
    - Supporting documents: Board of Trustees, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 1-12)
    - Supporting documents: Board of Visitors, 1814–1841 (Box 15, Folder 13-25)
    - Supporting documents: Board of Visitors, 1842–1886 (Box 16–17)
    - Supporting documents: Board of Visitors, 1886–1930 (Box 18, Folder 1-10)
    - Andover Creed subscriptions, 1841–1844 (Box 144, Folder 1-2)
    - Andover Creed subscriptions, 1850-1900, n.d. (Box 144, Folder 3)
- Faculty, Series II
  - Correspondence
    - Faculty correspondence, 1820-1916, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 1-11)
    - Faculty secretary correspondence, 1916–1923 (Box 139, Folder 12)
  - Course of Study
    - Christian Theology, 1822 (Box 136, Folder 5-6)
    - Christian Theology, 1822 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Christian Theology, 1825 (Box 136, Folder 7-8)
    - Christian Theology, 1825 (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Christian Theology, 1840 (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Minutes
    - Faculty minutes, 1845–1868 (Box 136, Folder 14)
    - Faculty minutes, 1866–1889 (Box 136, Folder 13)
    - Faculty minutes, 1889–1902 (Box 136, Folder 3)
    - Faculty minutes, 1902–1922 (Box 136, Folder 15-16)
  - Other records
    - Biographical sketches, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 13)
    - Other papers: general, 1807–1808 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - Other papers: general, 1811–1813 (Box 140, Folder 2-3)
    - Other papers: general, 1815–1824 (Box 140, Folder 4-13)
    - Other papers: general, 1825–1833 (Box 141, Folder 1-12)
    - Other papers: general, 1881–1922 (Box 141, Folder 13)
    - Other papers: general, n.d. (Box 141, Folder 14)
    - Other papers re: Pearson, Eliphalet, 1807-1822, n.d (Box 145, Folder 1-5)
    - Other papers re: Smyth, Egbert C., 1863-1913, n.d. (Box 145, Folder 6-7)
    - Other papers re: Stuart, Moses, 1809-1852, n.d. (Box 145, Folder 8-11)
    - Pamphlets: examinations and synopsis, 1884-1896, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 11, 15)
    - Papers re: preaching, 1810-1873, n.d. (Box 145, Folder 12-15)
    - Publications: newsletter, Faculty Letter, 1922–1926 (Box 139, Folder 14)
  - Syllabi
    - Biology, n.d. (Box 145, Folder 16)
    - Hypothesis, n.d. (Box 145, Folder 17)
    - Instruction in German, n.d. (Box 145, Folder 18)
    - Introductory Observation, n.d. (Box 146, Folder 1)
    - Other syllabi, n.d. (Box 146, Folder 2-4)
    - Pure Science, n.d. (Box 146, Folder 5-9)
    - Pure Science, n.d. (Box 147, Folder 1-2)
    - Sacred Rhetoric, 1829 (Box 136, Folder 4)
    - Sacred Rhetoric, 1829 (Box 65, Folder 12)
- Students, Series III
  - Applications
    - Alphabetical: A-W, 1908–1920 (Box 123, Folder 1-5)
    - Chronological, 1881–1899 (Box 123, Folder 6-21)
    - Chronological, 1900–1907 (Box 124, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence
    - Letters of certificate, 1865–1883 (Box 124, Folder 5-16)
    - Letters of certificate, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 18)
    - Letters re: Church membership, 1874–1885 (Box 127, Folder 10-22)
    - Letters re: Church membership, n.d. (Box 127, Folder 23)
    - Letters re: perspective students, A–Z, unidentified, 1917–1922 (Box 125, Folder 1-10)
  - Essays
    - Advanced class essays, 1884–1888 (Box 94, Folder 1-4)
    - Honorary scholarship examinations, 1885–1887 (Box 94, Folder 5-8)
    - Scholarship essays, 1884–1885 (Box 94, Folder 9-25)
    - Scholarship essays, 1886–1893 (Box 95–97)
  - Financial records
    - American College and Education Society (ACES) funds, 1875–1882 (Box 126, Folder 9-24)
    - American College and Education Society (ACES) funds, 1883–1892 (Box 127, Folder 1-8)
    - Other financial records, 1913–1914 (Box 127, Folder 9)
  - Lecture notes: large volumes
    - Anonymous, n.d. (Box 107)
    - Allson – Dunning (Box 108)
    - Dunning – Huntress, n.d. (Box 109)
    - Huntress – Ropes, n.d. (Box 110)
    - Ropes – Thayer, n.d. (Box 111)
    - Thayer – Willard, n.d. (Box 112)
    - Willard – Wright, n.d. (Box 113)
  - Lecture notes: small volumes
    - Anonymous – De Bevoise, n.d. (Box 114)
    - Fisher – Wood, n.d. (Box 115)
  - Other student records
    - Courses of study cards, 1899–1913 (Box 125, Folder 11-24)
    - Courses of study cards, 1913-1921, n.d. (Box 126, Folder 1-8)
    - List of students, 1883–1894 (Box 124, Folder 17)
    - Room assignments, 1821–1825 (Box 124, Folder 4)
    - Statistics, 1908-1920, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 17)
    - Student papers, ca.1907-1937 (Box 124, Folder 19)
  - Publications: newsletters
    - Andover Newton Chronicle, 1944–1945 (Box 138, Folder 1)
    - Andover-Newton Summer News, 1932–1933 (Box 138, Folder 2)
    - A.N.T.S. Bulletin/Hill, 1943–1944 (Box 138, Folder 3)
    - Bulletin, 1938–1946 (Box 138, Folder 4-8)
    - Hill View, 1946–1965 (Box 138, Folder 9-31)
    - Mount Zion A.N.T.S., 1943–1944 (Box 138, Folder 32)
    - Student Bulletin, 1941–1944 (Box 138, Folder 33)
  - Registers
    - Grade book, 1820–1896 (Box 122, Folder 5-6)
    - Student register, 1822–1921 (Box 120, Folder 1-6)
    - Student register, 1902 (Box 121)
    - Student register [#1], n.d. (Box 27)
    - Student register [#2], n.d. (Box 58)
    - Student register [#3-4], n.d. (Box 122, Folder 1-2)
    - Student register [#5], n.d. (Box 178)
  - Student organizations: Bartlet Atheneum
    - Agent: account book, 1825–1847 (Box 148, Folder 1)
    - Agent: correspondence and records, 1847–1852 (Box 138, Folder 34)
    - Agent: reports, 1826-1848, n.d. (Box 138, Folder 35)
    - Agent: subscription lists: ledger, 1887–1903 (Box 148, Folder 5)
    - Agent: subscription lists: ledger, n.d. (Box 138, Folder 36)
    - Other records: By-laws, n.d. (Box 138, Folder 37)
    - Other records: cash book, 1892–1908 (Box 148, Folder 4)
    - Other records: minutes, 1820–1840 (Box 148, Folder 3)
    - Other records: reports, general, 1825–1868 (Box 138, Folder 38)
    - Other records: reports, president, 1825–1834 (Box 138, Folder 39)
    - Secretary: correspondence and membership records, 1839-1843, n.d. (Box 138, Folder 40)
    - Secretary: reports, 1828–1833 (Box 138, Folder 41)
    - Treasurer: account book, 1819–1833 (Box 148, Folder 2)
    - Treasurer: receipts, 1834-1907, n.d. (Box 138, Folder 42-52)
    - Treasurer: reports, 1822–1868 (Box 138, Folder 53-54)
  - Student organizations: Lockhart Society (Musical Association for Sacred Music)
    - Circulation catalog, 1847–1848 (Box 149, Folder 2)
    - Concert programs, 1822-1861, n.d. (Box 149, Folder 1)
    - Concert programs, 1834 (Box 147, Folder 3)
    - Constitution and minutes, 1812–1881 (Box 149, Folder 3-6)
  - Student organizations: other organizations
    - Andover League for Work in Neglected Places, 1891–1984 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Gymnastic Association: accounts and minutes, 1852–1856 (Box 122, Folder 4)
    - OWLS: Constitution and minutes, 1877–1879 (Box 138, Folder 6)
  - Student organizations: Porter Rhetorical Society
    - Account book: treasurer, 1823–1849 (Box 160, Folder 1)
    - Account book: treasurer, 1875–1881 (Box 160, Folder 2)
    - Account book: treasurer, n.d. (Box 34)
    - Circulation catalog, 1831–1834 (Box 34)
    - Circulation catalog, 1849–1850 (Box 57)
    - Circulation catalog, 1855–1856 (Box 57)
    - Circulation catalog, 1847–1848 (Box 161, Folder 6)
    - Circulation catalog, 1856 (Box 161, Folder 2)
    - Circulation catalog, 1858 (Box 161, Folder 3)
    - Circulation catalog, n.d. (Box 55)
    - Constitution, 1832 (Box 158, Folder 20)
    - Constitution and records, 1823–1832 (Box 160, Folder 4)
    - Constitution and records, 1823–1834 (Box 160, Folder 5)
    - Constitution and records, 1825–1837 (Box 160, Folder 6)
    - Constitution and records, 1832–1846 (Box 161, Folder 1)
    - Constitution and records, 1832–1847 (Box 161, Folder 2)
    - Constitution and records, 1833–1836 (Box 161, Folder 3)
    - Constitution and records, 1836–1850 (Box 161, Folder 4)
    - Other records: addresses, president, 1824–1825 (Box 158, Folder 14)
    - Other records: book catalog, 1826 (Box 161, Folder 4)
    - Other records: book catalog, 1827–1839 (Box 158, Folder 15-16)
    - Other records: book catalog, 1843 (Box 161, Folder 5)
    - Other records: book lists, 1828-1838, n.d. (Box 158, Folder 17-19)
    - Other records: correspondence, 1826–1874 (Box 158, Folder 9-13)
    - Other records: other papers, 1837, n.d. (Box 158, Folder 21)
    - Other records: other reports, general, 1824–1848 (Box 163, Folder 1)
    - Other records: vouchers, 1824-1882, n.d. (Box 159, Folder 8-17)
    - Minutes: general, 1823–1843 (Box 159, Folder 18)
    - Minutes: general, 1843–1882 (Box 162)
    - Programs: anniversaries, 1826–1884 (Box 159, Folder 1-5)
    - Programs: public meetings, 1835–1880 (Box 159, Folder 6-7)
    - Committee reports and minutes: Ad Hoc Committee, 1832–1874 (Box 158, Folder 1)
    - Committee reports and minutes: Book Committee, 1824–1831 (Box 158, Folder 2)
    - Committee reports and minutes: Book Committee, 1825–1844 (Box 160, Folder 3)
    - Committee reports and minutes: Library Committee, 1824–1838 (Box 158, Folder 3)
    - Officer reports and minutes: Board of Managers, 1823-1863, n.d. (Box 158, Folder 4-5)
    - Officer reports and minutes: Librarian, 1852–1863 (Box 158, Folder 6)
    - Officer reports and minutes: Treasurer, 1824–1881 (Box 158, Folder 7-8)
  - Student organizations: Society of Brethren
    - Anniversaries: 150th anniversary material, 1956 (Box 151, Folder 8)
    - Anniversaries: 175th anniversary material, 1981 (Box 151, Folder 9)
    - Anniversaries: ABCFM, Centennial material, 1910 (Box 151, Folder 6)
    - Anniversaries: Haystack, Centennial correspondence, 1906 (Box 151, Folder 7)
    - Institutional correspondence: Auburn Theological Seminary, 1829–1841 (Box 150, Folder 1-2)
    - Institutional correspondence: Princeton Theological Seminary, 1828–1847 (Box 150, Folder 3-5)
    - Institutional correspondence: Yale Divinity School, 1828–1834 (Box 150, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence re: members in missionary work: Africa, 1835–1846 (Box 150, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence re: members in missionary work: Eastern Mediterranean, 1827–1847 (Box 150, Folder 8-9)
    - Correspondence re: members in missionary work: North American Indians, 1817–1844 (Box 150, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence re: members in missionary work: Sandwich Islands (Hawaii), 1827–1832 (Box 150, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence re: members in missionary work: South East Asia, 1830–1860 (Box 150, Folder 12-13)
    - Correspondence re: members not in missionary work, 1828–1862 (Box 151, Folder 1-5)
    - History: correspondence re: history of organization, 1929 (Box 151, Folder 10)
    - History: excerpts from records, 1876 (Box 151, Folder 11)
    - History: manuscript, Chapter in the History of American Missions 1890 (Box 151, Folder 12)
    - History: notes (Box 151, Folder 13)
    - Minutes, 1821–1870 (Box 151, Folder 1-2)
    - Other records: biographical sketches, ABCFM missionaries, n.d. (Box 150, Folder 14)
    - Other records: ATS members, n.d. (Box 151, Folder 3)
    - Other records: Constitution, 1828 (Box 150, Folder 16)
    - Other records: Constitution and cipher, 1808 (Box 150, Folder 15)
    - Other records: correspondence, other, 1810-1835, n.d. (Box 150, Folder 17)
    - Other records: membership books, 1808–1829 (Box 150, Folder 18)
    - Other records: reports, committee, 1828–1838 (Box 150, Folder 19)
  - Student organizations: Society of Inquiry on the Subject of Missions
    - Committees and officers:
      - Board of Managers: correspondence, 1811–1911 (Box 165, Folder 9-10)
      - Board of Managers: minutes, 1823–1903 (Box 167, Folder 4)
      - Board of Managers: reports, 1824–1861 (Box 165, Folder 11)
      - Colonization Committee: correspondence, 1823–1832 (Box 165, Folder 12-15)
      - Colonization Committee: reports, 1825–1831 (Box 165, Folder 16)
      - Committee of Correspondence: correspondence, 1812–1841 (Box 165, Folder 17-22)
      - Committee of Correspondence: reports, 1820–1840 (Box 165, Folder 23)
      - Committee on Domestic Missions: correspondence, 1826–1841 (Box 165, Folder 24-26)
      - Committee on Domestic Missions: minutes, 1826–1848 (Box 165, Folder 27)
      - Committee on Domestic Missions: reports, 1826-1840, n.d. (Box 165, Folder 28-29)
      - Committee on Nominal Christendom: records, 1841–1842 (Box 169, Folder 4)
      - Committee on Nominal Christendom: regulations, 1841 (Box 165, Folder 30)
      - Committee on Foreign Missions: correspondence, 1829–1840 (Box 165, Folder 31)
      - Committee on Foreign Missions: minutes, 1828–1841 (Box 167, Folder 2)
      - Committee on Foreign Missions: reports, 1828–1839 (Box 165, Folder 32)
      - Foreign Evangelical Committee: records, 1847, n.d. (Box 165, Folder 33)
      - Other committees: Book Committee, report, 1822 (Box 165, Folder 36)
      - Other committees: Committee of Agency, reports, 1823–1829 (Box 165, Folder 37)
      - Other committees: Committee of Investigations, records, 1831–1834 (Box 169, Folder 3)
      - Other committees: Committee on the Monthly Concert, report, 1825 (Box 165, Folder 38)
      - Other committees: Committee to Revise the Constitution, reports, 1823 (Box 165, Folder 39)
      - Other committees: Standing Committee, reports, 1813–1821 (Box 165, Folder 41)
      - Library Examining Committee: library catalog [#1-3], n.d. (Box 171, Folder 1-3)
      - Library Examining Committee: library catalog [#1-3], n.d. (Box 172, Folder 1-3)
      - Seaman's Committee: records, 1829–1942 (Box 169, Folder 6)
      - Seaman's Committee: records, 1830-1837, n.d. (Box 169, Folder 34)
      - Treasurer: account book, 1821–1906 (Box 170, Folder 3-4)
      - Treasurer: reports, 1815-1850, n.d. (Box 165, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence
      - Letters, 1804–1818 (Box 165, Folder 8)
      - Letters, 1810–1901 (Box 164, Folder 1-46)
      - Letters, 1815–1827 (Box 170, Folder 5)
      - Letters, 1902-1905, n.d. (Box 165, Folder 1-7)
    - Manuscripts
      - Abstract of Depons' Voyage, 1814 (Box 166, Folder 7)
      - Account of Mr. Charles Sherman, 1814 (Box 166, Folder 8)
      - Facts Concerning the Early Years of the Society of Inquiry in Andover Seminary [Andover, Massachusetts], 1899 (Box 166, Folder 9)
      - [Foreign Missions], 1797 (Box 166, Folder 10)
      - Gordon Hall, 1899 (Box 166, Folder 11)
      - Hindoo Mythology (Box 171, Folder 2)
      - History of the Society of Inquiry as Given before the Society, 1882 (Box 166, Folder 12)
      - Inquiry into the Moral Condition of Persia, 1831 (Box 166, Folder 13)
      - Journal Kept during a Tour through the Country of Columbia for the Purpose of Obtaining Religious Information, 1813 (Box 166, Folder 14)
      - Letters of Messrs. Schermerhorn and Mills to Rev. Dr. Holmes, Respecting the Western Indians (Box 166, Folder 15)
      - Memories of American Missions, Loomis letters, 1820–1878 (Box 165, Folder 44-52)
      - Narrative of the Religious State of the Counties of West Chester, Putnam, and Dutchess in the State of New York (Box 170, Folder 1)
      - North American Indians, 1830 (Box 166, Folder 16)
      - Report of Labors in Salem, 1818 (Box 166, Folder 17)
      - Sketches of the Burman Empire, 1830 (Box 166, Folder 18)
    - Minutes
      - Meeting minutes, 1844–1857 (Box 167, Folder 3)
      - Meeting minutes, 1857–1872 (Box 167, Folder 1)
      - Meeting minutes, 1873–1911 (Box 168, Folder 1)
      - Meeting minutes, 1917–1920 (Box 167, Folder 5)
    - Other records
      - Anniversaries: address, 1839 (Box 166, Folder 1)
      - Anniversaries, 1891 (Box 166, Folder 2)
      - Anniversaries: programs, 1834-1908, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 3-6)
      - Biographical sketches, 1825–1833 (Box 166, Folder 19)
      - Constitution, 1884 (Box 166, Folder 20)
      - Constitution and membership (volumes 1-3) (Box 168, Folder 2-4)
      - Dissertations, n.d. (Box 172–173)
      - Other papers, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 21)
      - Pamphlets and letters re: religious condition of colleges, 1856–1878 (Box 166, Folder 22-23)
      - Bishop Mar Yohannan (rolled poster), 1842 (Box MC3)
      - Programs: public meetings, 1871–1875 (Box 166, Folder 24)
      - Record book of orders, 1814–1827 (Box 169, Folder 1)
      - Reference book re: missionary societies, 1812 (Box 166, Folder 25)
      - Subjects discussed: papers, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 26)
      - Subjects discussed: record book, 1811–1841 (Box 169, Folder 2)
      - Vouchers, n.d. (Box 165, Folder 42-43)
- Alumni, Series IV
  - Alumni Association: administrative
    - 100th anniversary material, 1908 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Account book: treasurer, 1895–1918 (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - Announcements, circulars, etc., 1895–1927 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Autographs, alumni, 1897 (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - Autographs, alumni, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, general, 1845–1955 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, general, 1906–1919 (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - Directories, alumni, 1895–1900 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Lists of alumni, 1810-1844, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - Meeting correspondence, 1845 (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Meeting correspondence, 1846 (Box 98, Folder 8)
    - Meeting minutes, 1826–1867 (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Meeting minutes, 1878–1884 (Box 98, Folder 9)
    - Meeting minutes, 1890–1932 (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - Publication: Alumni Letter, 1905 (Box 98, Folder 20)
    - Report: Committee of Conference, 1906 (Box 98, Folder 21)
    - Sermons, alumni, n.d. (Box 144, Folder 14-15)
  - Alumni Association: necrologies
    - Biographical sketches, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - Lists, 1868 (Box 98, Folder 10-13)
    - Lists, 1916 (Box 98, Folder 14)
    - Lists, 1940 (Box 98, Folder 15-16)
    - Lists, 1951 (Box 98, Folder 17-18)
    - Notes, 1858 (Box 98, Folder 19)
    - Published, 1880 (Box 99, Folder 1-3)
    - Published, 1880 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Published, 1890 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Published, 1890 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Published, 1894 (Box 99, Folder 6-12)
  - Class material
    - Class of 1854: biographical sketches, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - Class of 1857: biographical sketches, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 6)
    - Class of 1857: [items removed from #100.6], n.d. (Box 100, Folder 7)
    - Class of 1857: general material, 1861 (Box 98, Folder 22)